

 $\searrow$ 

saquibnazeer05@gmail.com



9330791287



Howrah, India



linkedin.com/in/saquibnazeer



github.com/delta9874

## **SKILLS**

AWS

Python



lambda

Boto3

Cloudformation



IAM

AWS Developer

AWS Solutions Architect

Json

Yaml

#### LANGUAGES

English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

# Saquib Nazeer

AWS Cloud Engineer/DevOps Engineer

Passionate about Cloud Technologies and DevOps, Successfully Completed AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate, AWS CLF-01 Certification. Looking forward for challenging roles in AWS. Joined TCS as Digital Cadre Candidate got 3 awards for consistent dedicated effort for the Project. Interested for opportunities in AWS Engineer / DevOps Engineer for Containers on ECS and EKS.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **AWS Cloud Engineer**

Tata Consultancy Services

09/2020 - Present

Role

Working as AWS Engineer, For Data Center Migration to AWS Cloud using standard cloud native approach for Australian media giant Foxtel. We are leveraging AWS resource such as EC2,RDS,FSx,S3, Lambda,DMS, Data Sync,Cloud Endure, Direct Connect etc.

Kolkata

- Successfully Migrated Foxtel's IDM solution "ForgeRock" to AWS, Responsible for One of the Critical migration of our Project we are migrating DWH solution form on-premises to AWS.
- Implemented automation with lambda on for various services like Instance Reboot, Updating Auto Scaling group AMI, Centralized Instance Scheduler for EC2 and RDS using Boto3.

### **ORGANIZATIONS**

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd., Kolkata (09/2020 - Present)

System Engineer(TCS Digital)

## **CERTIFICATES**

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (10/2021 - 10/2024)

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (06/2021 - 06/2024)

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals AZ-900 (11/2021)

## **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

Indoor Navigation System (12/2018 - 01/2019)

■ Part Of my Internship In Airport Authority of India

Credit Default Prediction Model (02/2019 - 05/2019)

Credit Default Dataset From UCI ,Tiwan ,Japan .Dataset :- https://www.kaggle.com/uciml/default-of-credit-card-clients-dataset using Python

### **EDUCATION**

#### Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech), Computer Science (8.6 CGPA)

Kalyani Government Engineering College

2020 - 2020

Senior Secondary (XII), Science (85%)

Abhinav Bharati High School

2013 - 2015

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Star Of Month Awards , Couple of On-Spot Awards , Quarter Achiver Award